If you are sleepy,
rest early.
I am a disaster to the nation right now.
Since you haven't slept,
how dare I sleep?
Eunuch Jingyuan.
You must not lose your manners.
Your Majesty.
The little prince was framed for adultery with Consort Rong.
The Eldest Princess just sent people to catch them.
Now the little prince
has been forcibly taken away.
What did you say?
The Eldest Princess clearly lives outside the palace.
But she came in the middle of the night
to catch adulterers.
I am afraid this
is targeted at me.
The one about to be executed
is Your Majesty's most beloved brother.
Summon
Si Xinglan immediately.
Why did Your Majesty summon me?
I would like to ask Her Highness the Grand Princess.
What did you do to Ayan?
Si Xingyan had an affair with His Majesty's Consort Rong.
He defiled the inner palace,
and lost all decency.
I am His Majesty's aunt.
Naturally, I must consider his reputation.
So I must deal with Si Xingyan properly.
Ayan is simple-minded.
I fear someone framed him.
Framed?
He is a prince.
If His Majesty didn't give the order,
who would dare touch him?
According to the ancestral system,
royal family members must go to their fiefs upon coming of age.
Yet Ayan has always stayed in the palace,
which is certainly against the rules.
Now that such a thing has happened,
I think it's time to send him away.
Is that so?
To me, it looks like
you want Ayan's life.
Hahaha.
Anyway,
I am the biological aunt of Your Majesty and Ayan.
If not for your sake,
I wouldn't have brought this up.
Ayan only has the mind of a seven-year-old.
If you make him go to his fief,
you are sending him to his death.
Even if he lacks intelligence,
he is an adult man.
His illness is in his brain,
not his body.
You must never treat him as a child.
It seems, Aunt,
you are determined to force me.
This matter is of great importance.
Forgive me, but I cannot yield.
If Your Majesty insists on protecting Si Xingyan,
then I will summon the ministers,
and let the whole court judge carefully
who is right and who is wrong.
Your Majesty.
Both the Grand Princess and Consort Rong are suspects.
I hope Your Majesty
will investigate thoroughly.
How dare you block the Grand Princess's way!
Do you have a death wish?
Then can I block it?
What are you doing, Your Majesty?
Didn't you want to punish A'yan severely, Aunt?
If so,
why not hand over Consort Rong and A'yan
so I can convict them?
Consort Rong and A'yan have committed a grave crime,
and I have already arrested them.
I'm afraid it's inconvenient for Your Majesty to personally try such a trivial matter.
Aunt, if you refuse to hand over Consort Rong and A'yan,
think I'm blind,
and convict them yourself,
don't blame me for suspecting you of plotting to murder A'yan
and committing treason.
What are you talking about, Your Majesty?
If this matter blows up,
it will damage the royal family's reputation.
Therefore, I wanted to keep it quiet
and arrest the person myself.
If Your Majesty doesn't care about your reputation,
I will simply hand the person over.
Handing the person over so easily,
there must be something fishy.
Your Majesty is close to Ayan.
I naturally understand.
And exactly because of this,
I fear Your Majesty might protect Ayan
and damage the royal reputation.
How about this?
You can take Consort Rong back for interrogation first.
If her words are false,
it won't be too late for me to hand Ayan over.
What?
Does Your Majesty not want to interrogate?
Guards!
Go fetch Consort Rong.
I will personally interrogate her thoroughly.
Yes.
Trying to start with Consort Rong?
Si Xingxuan,
you are just wasting your effort.
I truly love the young prince.
Please grant my request, Your Majesty.
I know you are lying.
As long as you tell the truth,
His Majesty
will have someone send you out of the palace.
Really?
I am the Emperor.
I keep my word.
I don't need to leave the palace.
As long as you can save my sister,
I will tell you the truth.
Where is your sister now?
I don't know.
I only know
they relocate at any time.
Before this,
she had been in the Grand Princess's mansion.
As long as you are willing to testify,
I will send someone to find her right now
and ensure her safety.
Unless I see my sister,
I won't tell you anything.
Given my aunt's methods,
she will definitely impeach Yan tomorrow morning.
If we can't find it tonight,
there won't be a tomorrow.
I'll go stall for time.
Your Highness.
His Majesty didn't find out anything yesterday.
The ministers have signed,
willing to jointly impeach the young prince.
Are you going to the palace, Your Highness?
Before His Majesty uncovers the truth,
I must present the ministers' joint impeachment memorial.
This way,
the initiative will still be in my hands.
Are we really going to impeach that fool?
If His Majesty wants to make a move against me,
I will make a move against Si Xingyan.
If he knows what's good for him,
and comes to me now to beg for mercy and apologize,
I might still forgive him.
Your Highness, someone is asking to see you.
Yes.
It seems His Majesty knows what's good for him.
Let him in.
Jing Yuan of Yuqing Palace pays respects to the Grand Princess.
A eunuch.
Is there no one left by His Majesty's side?
I am not here for His Majesty.
I am here for the little prince.
The little prince is kind-hearted.
Please spare his life.
I have seen Your Highness treat the little prince with kindness,
and surely you wouldn't bear to see him sent to the frontier to die in vain.
Please reconsider, Your Highness.
Why do you say that?
I love A'yan very much.
But,
he made a mistake a man shouldn't make.
He fell in love with the Emperor's woman.
I cannot forgive him.
Bring the memorial.
Your Highness. Your Highness.
Your Highness.